Guide to the Kappa Omicron Nu records, 1919-1999.
Kappa Omicron Nu records, 1919-1999.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kappa Omicron Nu records, 1919-1999.
23-2-2702
Kappa Omicron Nu Honor Society. Mu Chapter.
3.4 cubic ft.
Administrative records, annual reports, scrapbooks,photographs, corporate charter
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Records of the Mu chapter of Kappa Omicron Nu.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Mu Chapter of Omicron Nu, a national home economics honor society, was founded at Cornell in 1919. Dr. Georgia L. White of the Michigan Agricultural College acted as the installing officer. The aims of the organization were to promote scholarship and to further home economics education at Cornell. The chapter also provided a scholarship to the freshman woman in Home Economics with the highest scholastic standing. In 1990, Omicron Nu merged with Kappa Omicron Phi to form Kappa Omicron Nu Honor Society.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes membership records and membership book; information about scholarships; minutes of meetings, 1920-1989; secretary's book, 1936-1942; records of events; presidents' annual reports, 1940s-1960s; scrapbook about the founding of the chapter, 1919; photographs; and programs, and the original charter from 1919.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kappa Omicron Nu Honor Society.; Cornell University--Societies.; New York State College of Home Economics.--Societies, etc.; New York State College of Home Economics.--Students.; Omicron Nu.Mu Chapter
Subjects:
Women college students.; Greek letter societies.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Awards/Scholarships
Box 1, folders 22-26; Box 5
Series II. Correspondence
Box 1, folders 8-11, 58-59
Series III. Events
Events
Box 1, folders 27, 47-50
Honors Day
Box 1, folder 51
Foreign Students' Tea
Box 1, folder 52
Series IV. Meeting Minutes
Box 1, folders 29-38
Series V. Membership Files
Membership Files
Box 1, folders 12-21, 40-42; Box 2
Henry Ricciuti
Box 1, folder 61
David Knapp
Box 1, folder 60
Officers
Box 1, folders 39, 55-56
Series VI. Photographs
Box 1, folder 28; Box 3
Series VII. Publications
Series VIII. Reports
Box 1, folders 57, 68
Series IX. Scrapbooks/Charter
Box 3
Series X. Subject Files
Box 1, folders 1-3, 43-46, 54, 62-63
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Awards/Scholarships
  - Scholarship Information-1940's, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Information Concerning Scholarships, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Outstanding Undergraduate Award (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Distinguished Teaching Award (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Kathy Conrad Memorial Fund, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Plaque Recognizing Outstanding Sophomores, 1956-1973 (Box 5)
  - Fall - Eligible Students, Initiation Cards, Awards, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Initiation Certificates, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fall - Initiation, Eligible Students - Awards, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Initiation Cards, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Fall, Spring
  - Initiation Cards, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Spring
  - Spring Initiation: Scholarship Recipients, Recommendations, Letters, Meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Awards, Elections, Special Activities, Membership Directory, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Association of College Honor Societies Information Booklet, Scholarships/Awards, Special Activities, Elections, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Distinguished Teaching Award (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Memos on finding faculty advisors, strengths/weaknesses of chapter (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Information about Omicron Nu, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter: Starting of Omicron Nu, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Series III. Events
  - Events
    - Human Ecology Day and Exposition, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Events Planned by Omicron Nu, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Sponsored Activities, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Events Planned, 1978; 1980 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Guidelines, Recommendations, Activities, 1982-1989 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Honors Day
    - Honors Day, 1965; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Foreign Students' Tea
    - Foreign Students' Tea (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Spring - Eligible Students, Activities, Initiation, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Elections, Name Change, Notes, Activities, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series IV. Meeting Minutes
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1970-1979; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Copy of minutes, 1920-1929 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Series V. Membership Files
  - Membership cards in alphabetical order, 1919-1992 (Box 2)
  - Leather book containing the signatures of members, 1919-1964 (Box 3)
  - Certificate of incorporation, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Nomination of Faculty Members, 1958; 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Recommendations for graduate students, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Membership Lists, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Initiates and Members, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Initiates and Members, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Initiation and Recruitment Reports, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Pledging and Initiation Ceremonies (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Treasurers' Reports, Financial Records, 1940-1949; 1955-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Information concerning donated pins and badges (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Information on Electing Members, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Information on Electing Members, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Completed Membership Blanks, Honorary Members, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - New Members, Reports, Awards, Eligible Students, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fall - Eligible Students, Programs, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fall Initiation - New Members, Initiation Cards and Certificates, Letters and Invitations, List of Eligible Students, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Spring Initiation - Letters and Invitations, List of Eligible Students, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fall Initiation - Programs, New Members, Invitations, Eligible Students, Initiation Cards, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fall Initiation - Initiation Cards, Invitations to Membership; Spring Initiation - Program, Reports, Invitations, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Fall Initiation - List of Eligible Students, Recommendations, Invitees, Letters from National Chapter, Program, Correspondence, Initiation Cards, Membership Recruitment Report, Chapter Remittance Form, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Spring Initiation - Program, List of New Members, List of Current Members, Initiation Cards, Invitations/Applications, Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Fall Initiation - Initiates, Initiation Financial Forms, Officers and Addresses, Correspondence; Spring Initiation - Initiation Financial Forms, Members (Full and Junior), Program, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Fall Initiation - Eligible Students, List of Members, List of Initiates, Elections, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu pins from four distinguished members (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu stamp (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Fall Minority Hosting, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Programs Initiation- Cards, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Fall
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Initiation cards, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Initiation cards, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON) HEAA, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Initiation cards, 2001 (Box 4)
    Spring, Fall
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bill Rosen's KON Nomination, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Quill and Dagger, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Initiation cards, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Sphinx Head Society, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2003 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Initiation cards, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2003 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Initiation cards, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Kappa Omicron NU (KON), 2004 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Initiation cards, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Initiation Cards, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Kappa Omicron Nu (KON), 2005 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Initiation cards, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Initiation cards and financial report, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Initiation cards, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Initiation cards and financial report, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Initiation cards and financial report, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Initiation cards and financial report, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Initiation cards, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Initiation cards and financial report, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Initiation cards, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Initiation cards, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Henry Ricciuti
    - Dr. Henry Ricciuti, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - David Knapp
    - Dr. David Knapp-Member, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Officers
    - Secretary's Book, 1936-1942 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Officers, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Officers, 1976-1989 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Series VI. Photographs
  - Conclaves, Photos, 1957; 1959,; 1961,; 1963,; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
  - Contact sheets and photographs, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Series VII. Publications
  - Directories (Box 3)
  - Handbook (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Handbook (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Secretary's Book, 1936-1942 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Honor Society Booklets (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Certificates, Flyers, Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publicity (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Programs and Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stationery (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets/Brochures (Box 3)
  - Newsletter, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Chapter Newsletters, 1999-09; 2000-09; 2001-03; 2001-09 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Papers/Articles about Home Economics and Omicron Nu, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1920-1921 (Box 2)
    Volume 1, no.1,2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1921-1922 (Box 2)
    Volume 2, no.1,2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1922-1923 (Box 2)
    Volume 3, no.1,2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1923-1924 (Box 2)
    Volume 4, no.1,2,3
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1925 (Box 2)
    Volume 5, no.1,2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1927 (Box 2)
    Volume 6, no.2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1927 (Box 2)
    Volume 7, no.1
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1928 (Box 2)
    Volume 8, no.2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1937 (Box 2)
    Volume 16, no.2
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1957 (Box 2)
    Volume 31, no.1
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1961-1963 (Box 2)
    Volume 33, no.1,2, 4
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    Volume 34, no.1,3
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    Volume 35, no.2,4
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    Volume 36, no.1,3
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1969-1971 (Box 2)
    Volume 37, no.1,2,3,4
  - Publication - "Omicron Nu", 1971-1973 (Box 2)
    Volume 38, no.1,2,4
  - Publication - "Dialogue", 1992-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publication - "Dialogue", 2009-11 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publication - "Forum", 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - President's Handbook, 2005-2007 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - New Member's Handbook, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Advisor's Handbook, 2006-2008 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series VIII. Reports
  - Presidents' Annual Reports, 1940-1969 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Programs and Reports, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Spring - New Members, Financial Report, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Spring - Initiation, New Members, Financial Report, National Reports, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Activities, Pictures, Awards/Scholarships, Reports and Forms for National Group, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mu Chapter Constitution, Bylaws, Budget, Annual Financial Reports (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Series IX. Scrapbooks/Charter
  - Scrapbooks/Chapter, 1919-1970 (Box 3)
    includes photographs
- Series X. Subject Files
  - Miscellaneous, 1976; 1979,; 1980,; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Announcements, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Announcements, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Report Forms sent to National Omicron Nu, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Advice to the President, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Reading List, Articles, Ritual Forms, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - National Programs of Work, 1950-1969; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Selection of Class Marshalls, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Omicron Nu Bylaws (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - National Omicron Nu information, 1960-1969; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 63)